Welcome to CTL SC1x Fundamentals of Supply Chain
Management and Logistics.
In this lecture, all I want to do
is introduce concepts of Supply Chain Management and Logistics,
and set the stage for the remainder of the course.
But first, let's talk about some supply
chains for a few different products.
And so what I'm showing here are four very different products
that you would think have very different supply chains.
And you'd be right.
In the top left, we have bananas being
sold in a U.S. grocery store.
On the right, we have an integrated ignition assembly.
On the bottom right, we have women's pumps.
On the bottom left, we have a bunch
of bags of cement-- of concrete.
So if you look at these, you'd think, wow!
There's nothing that could be similar in these supply chains.
And the interesting thing about supply chain management